<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>homelab on ./rolando.anton.sh</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/categories/homelab/</link><description>Recent content in homelab on ./rolando.anton.sh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rolando.anton.sh/categories/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Lab Part 3: Building the first version of my home lab</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing3/</guid><description>After the prelude of the previous posts, now its time to share the experiences I had while building my home lab that had three iterations.
I set a group of criteria during the planing of the build of the equipment I wanted to use in the first iteration of my home lab. The main ones are:
RAM Capacity: Because the primary use case is to run virtual machines, the number of virtual machines depends directly on the amount of RAM.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 2: Skills and resources before build one</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing2/</guid><description>To continue with the previous post about home labs before I started to plan and build mine, I would like to recommend a set of topics or skills to learn or improve the knowledge that I consider where very important to have when I started to build my home lab.
Learning Linux If you are in TI or you plan to do it, there is no valid reason not to learn Linux/Unix.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 1: Why build one?</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/homelabbing1/</guid><description>So, as I mentioned in the first post of the blog, the homelab topic is going to be frequent in this blog. And I would like to start sharing my experience of why I decided to start a home lab.
There are many ways to gain or maintain knowledge, and it may be theoretical or practical, in the best-case scenario both. I spent many years installing and supporting network security solutions and when I started to work as a Systems Engineer at Fortinet, everything changed, especially the ways I have to develop expertise in topics outside the realm of the product portfolio.</description></item></channel></rss>