<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Rolando Anton - Cybersecurity for fun and profit</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Rolando Anton - Cybersecurity for fun and profit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>© 2020 Rolando Anton, all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why every security professional needs to embrace DevOps and automation</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/10/14/why-every-security-professional-needs-to-embrace-devops-and-automation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/10/14/why-every-security-professional-needs-to-embrace-devops-and-automation/</guid><description>If you are a cybersecurity professional, or you plan to become one, at some point, you had or have to deal with building an infrastructure for research, learning, or test something as part of your daily job.
About 20 years ago, I found a text written by Eric Raymond called &amp;quot;How to become a hacker,&amp;quot; and the section that I would like to highlight is the attitude:
World is full of problems waiting to be solved.</description></item><item><title>HOME LAB PART 5: The Ultimate Small Form Factor Server for Home Lab</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/09/12/home-lab-part-5-the-ultimate-small-form-factor-server-for-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/09/12/home-lab-part-5-the-ultimate-small-form-factor-server-for-home-lab/</guid><description>Introduction Today I'm going to share the result of my experience building my home lab. As mentioned in my previous post as a spoiler, I shrank my setup even more and ended with a Mini ITX system bringing together two worlds: &amp;quot;/r/sffpc/&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;r/homelab/.&amp;quot; Also, as you may guess from the header, I moved my setup from Intel to AMD for the CPU, and this is also my first setup using AMD.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 4: Shrinking/Consolidating Home Lab</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/08/15/home-lab-part-4-shrinking/consolidating-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/08/15/home-lab-part-4-shrinking/consolidating-home-lab/</guid><description>And before getting into the server upgrade details, I started to consolidate and optimize the space usage of my home lab; all the devices I had in the rack were short-deep appliances, between 9&amp;quot; deep and some of them even less. While researching, I found an interesting fact, pro audio equipment also uses the 1U format, and most of them are short-deep too.
There are many 1U portable cases in the market.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 3: Building the first version of my home lab</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/05/15/home-lab-part-3-building-the-first-version-of-my-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/05/15/home-lab-part-3-building-the-first-version-of-my-home-lab/</guid><description>Now its time to share the experiences I had while building my home lab. Keep in mind that I began this project back in March 2016. First, I set a group of criteria during the planing of the build of the equipment I wanted to use in the first iteration of my server.
The main ones was:
RAM Capacity: Because the primary use case is to run virtual machines, the number of virtual machines depends directly on the amount of RAM, the 16 GB of RAM I had on my laptop back then wasn't enough.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 2: Skills and resources before build one</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/11/home-lab-part-2-skills-and-resources-before-build-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/11/home-lab-part-2-skills-and-resources-before-build-one/</guid><description>To continue with the previous post about home labs before I started to plan and build mine, I would like to recommend a set of topics or skills to learn or improve the knowledge that I consider where very important to have when I started to build my home lab.
Learning Linux If you are in TI or you plan to do it, there is no valid reason not to learn Linux/Unix.</description></item><item><title>Home Lab Part 1: Why build one?</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/06/home-lab-part-1-why-build-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/06/home-lab-part-1-why-build-one/</guid><description>So, as I mentioned in the first post of the blog, the homelab topic is going to be frequent in this blog. And I would like to start sharing my experience of why I decided to start a home lab.
There are many ways to gain or maintain knowledge, and it may be theoretical or practical, in the best-case scenario both. I spent many years installing and supporting network security solutions and when I started to work as a Systems Engineer at Fortinet, everything changed, especially the ways I have to develop expertise in topics outside the realm of the product portfolio.</description></item><item><title>hello world</title><link>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/05/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rolando.anton.sh/blog/2020/04/05/hello-world/</guid><description>I couldn't find a better way to start something with the classic &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot;. The idea of this blog is to communicate, share knowledge and experiences of my everyday interaction with technology. I'm lucky and very grateful to do what I love as a daily job. And during my free time, I like to keep learning and stay current, and for that, I built my home lab, which can be a whole dedicated topic (I'm going to share a lot about this).</description></item></channel></rss>